<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Axenide - general</title>
    <subtitle>I do things.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://axeni.de/tags/general/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://axeni.de"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://axeni.de/tags/general/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Hello, World!</title>
        <published>2025-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-12-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://axeni.de/blog/hello/"/>
        <id>https://axeni.de/blog/hello/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://axeni.de/blog/hello/">&lt;p&gt;I decided to migrate my website to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.getzola.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Zola&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a static site generator written in Rust.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;trix.is-a.dev&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Trix&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; made a site using the same theme, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ametrine.daudix.one&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Ametrine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and I really liked how it looked. So I thought, why not? After all, I’ve wanted to turn my site into a sort of personal blog for quite a while now.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It itches a bit because I’m used to building my own tools and having full control over what I do. But I also want something that works well and doesn’t require as much maintenance. I have many pending projects and I don’t want to add more work to my list.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A clear sign of my tendency to want to control everything is my move to Linux (about 4 years ago now) and projects like &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;Axenide&#x2F;Ax-Shell&quot;&gt;Ax-Shell&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or its successor &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;Axenide&#x2F;Ambxst&quot;&gt;Ambxst&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. But sometimes, it’s better to use existing tools that work well instead of reinventing the wheel.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Sometimes” is actually “most of the time,” but when it comes to creating, &lt;em&gt;sometimes&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; it’s inevitable to want to do it all yourself. :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, this is the part where I start talking about my feelings and motivations. But I’d like to go into more detail about that in a future entry (and maybe in a video, since I’m really looking forward to returning to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtube.com&#x2F;Axenide&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, I’ve wanted to have a website since I was a kid, and when I finally learned how… Social media happened. I felt like the purpose was lost, that it no longer made sense to have a personal site. Social networks have their algorithms, infrastructure, and community, and it’s easier to reach people there.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in recent years, I’ve felt a lot of nostalgia for the classic web, for those personal sites and blogs I used to visit. I want to recapture that feeling and share my thoughts, projects, and experiences in a more authentic and personal way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-s-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, like many things I do, this is an experiment. I don’t know exactly where it will lead me, or if I’ll have the consistency to maintain it. But I want to try.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And well, that’s it. I had to hold myself back from writing a full essay in this first entry, which makes me realize I have a lot to say. So, I might actually be active after all. :)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
